careersandjobsuk.com 2012-06-23

# careers and jobs UK - Privacy Policy

##  Why we collect your data? 

By collecting your data, it allows us to understand what your needs and wants are, provide personalised content and match the most relevant adverts and services for you. It also, allows us to provide many great, targeted reader offers and services that we know you may be interested to hear about. 

##  Who is the Data Controller? 

When you provide personal information to CareersandJobsUK, the data controller is Careers-Jobs Limited. Please note that the Site's Servers are hosted in USA and therefore all data stored on this site is crossing International Borders from the EU to the USA. This has no effect on the treatment of your data due to the similarity in Data Protection between these 2 zones. 

If another company is the data controller, this will be made clear when you provide your personal information. 

##  How we use personal data 

The data controller will use your information together with other information for administration (including providing any goods, services or information you have requested), marketing, credit scoring, customer services and profiling your purchasing preferences. We will disclose your information to our service providers and agents for these purposes. 

##  Consent 

By returning or submitting a form with your personal information to us, you consent to: 

  1. our processing your sensitive personal data such as health data for the above purposes; and
  2. our transferring your information to countries, which do not provide the same level of data protection as the UK if necessary for the above purposes. If we do make such a transfer, we will put a contract in place to ensure your information is protected.

When you give us your personal information, we will give you the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications by post or telephone from us but remember that this will preclude you from receiving any of our special offers or promotions in future. We will also give you the opportunity to opt in to receive such information by e-mail or SMS and will only send it to you if you do opt in or if you are an existing customer and the information relates to similar goods or services to those, which you have previously requested from us. 

You may also exercise your right to opt out of the use of your information for marketing purposes at any time by contacting us by the methods explained at the end of this notice. 

Your personal information will be disclosed where we are obliged or permitted by law to do so. If you post or send offensive or objectionable content anywhere on or to any of our websites or otherwise engage in any disruptive behaviour on any of our websites, we can use whatever information that is available to us about you to stop such behaviour. This may involve informing relevant third parties such as your employer and law enforcement agencies about the content and your behaviour. 

##  Third Parties 

We would like to share your information with organisations who are our business partners. They may contact you by mail or telephone to let you know about any goods, services or promotions, which may be of interest to you. We will always give you an option to opt out at the point where you give us your details. You may also be contacted by email or SMS should you opt-in to these methods of communications. We will never supply your information to a third party for marketing purposes if you tell us not to. 

You may also exercise your right to opt out of the use of your information being supplied to a third party, for marketing purposes at any time, by contacting us by the methods explained at the end of this notice. 

##  Cookies 

When you visit one of our websites, we may send you a cookie. A cookie is a small file that can be placed on your computer's hard disk for record keeping purposes and we may use them to do a number of things: 

  * Cookies help us to recognise you when you next visit one of our websites and note the advertisements displayed to you. This allows us to tailor the advertisements we provide to your preferences. We may use the services of third party ad servers for this purpose.
  * Cookies may be used to compile anonymous statistics related to the take up or use of services, or to patterns of browsing. A third party collects such data on our behalf to measure web site performance. Information collected is aggregated for reporting purposes. No personally identifiable information is collected by this service. The use of this service assists us in measuring and improving the structure and ease of use of our web sites.

##  Third Party Cookies 

Advertisements on our site are on occasion provided by another organisation. Our advertising partner will serve ads that it believes are most likely to be of interest to you, based on information about your visit to this and other websites (this information is anonymous in that it does not include your name, street address, e-mail address or telephone number). In order to do this, our advertising partner may need to place a cookie (a small text file) on your computer. For more information about this type of online behavioural advertising, about cookies, and about how to turn this feature off, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.co.uk](http://www.youronlinechoices.co.uk/). Cookies may be used to allow the advertisers to compile anonymous statistics, personalise advertising content and monitor the effectiveness of their campaigns. We cannot control nor do we have access to any cookies placed on your computer by third party advertisers and sponsors. 

##  Credit checks 

If you apply for credit then to help us to make credit decisions about you, to prevent fraud, to check your identity and to prevent money laundering, we may search the files of credit reference agencies who will record any credit searches on your file. We may also disclose details of how you conduct your account to such agencies. The information will be used by other credit grantors for making credit decisions about you and the people with whom you are financially associated for fraud prevention, money laundering prevention and occasionally for tracing debtors. 

##  Updating or deleting your personal information 

When you register online with any of Careers-Jobs Limited 's brands, you can see, review and change your personal information by logging onto the site and going to "My Account or equivalent". Please ensure you update your personal information if it changes or is inaccurate. Should you request that your account is closed and your personal information removed, please be assured that this will be done as soon as is reasonably possible. Personal information from closed accounts is retained in order to comply with legal obligations, prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems etc, but always done within a legal framework. 

When you request to be removed from further marketing offers, you will be added to a suppression list to ensure your request is complied with. All personal data is processed in line with the requirements of the Data Protection Act 1998 and The Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003. 

##  Personal data disclosed in public areas 

Certain Careers-Jobs Limited Ltd websites allow for the sharing of information. You should remember that any personal data you submit to such areas will be viewed by other third parties this includes, online chat rooms and forums. As such, your personal data may be viewed, collected and used by third parties over whom we have no control. We are not responsible for either the information you submit/post or otherwise make available in such public areas or any use that may be made of such information by any third party. 

##  Information Requests 

You have a right to ask for a copy of your information (for which we charge a small fee) and to ask us to correct any inaccuracies in your personal information (which is free). To make sure we follow your instructions correctly and to improve our service to you through training of our staff, we may monitor or record telephone calls. 

When you give us information about another person, you confirm that they have appointed you to act for them, to consent to the processing of their personal data, including sensitive personal data and to the transfer of their information abroad and to receive on their behalf any data protection notices. 

##  Notification of changes 

From time to time, we may make changes to the Privacy Policy. This may be in relation to changes in the law, best practice or changes in our services. 

##  How to contact us 

By email: | [info@careersandjobsuk.com](mailto:rudy@careersandjobsuk.com)  
---|---  
By telephone: | 0207 207 1854  
By mail: |  Data Protection Enquiries,  
Data Protection & Compliance Officer,  
Careers-Jobs Limited ,  
69 Silverthorne Road ,  
London, SW8 3HH   
  
**General information about data protection may be found at:**
